# Meng-Jiun Chiou

#### Taipei, Taiwan

coldmanck@gmail.com http://coldmanck.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/coldmanck

#### SUMMARY

I am an ambitious student embracing computer science, mainly on computer vision (CV), machine learning (ML) and multimedia processing. I love to learn new techniques and implement great ideas came up to my mind. Up to now, I have been working on not only a variety of research projects related to computer vision but also several interesting inclass projects with multiple programming languages, e.g. C, C++, Java, Python and Matlab.

#### SKILLS

Java

• C, C++

Matlab

- · Python
- Computer Vision
- · Social Skills
- Chinese
- English

Japanese

· Taiwanese

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Academia Sinica

12 / 2015 - Present

Research Assistant (RA)

I have been conducting research concerning to computer vision and machine learning at Multimedia and Machine Learning (MML) LAB since December, 2015.

#### Microsoft Taiwan

07 / 2013 - 06 / 2014

R&D Groups, Microsoft Student Partners (MSPs)

During my internship, I developed several Windows Apps (for instance, NHK Reader which was available in Sep. 2013 has 7,000+ downloads so far) and made speech for students to help people being more familiar with Microsoft techniques and services.

## EDUCATION

## National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

09 / 2012 - 06 / 2016

Bachelor of Science (BS), Electrical and Computer Engineering

- · Vice President, Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association
- · Photography Club

#### The University of Tokyo (UTokyo)

10/2014 - 09/2015

Exchange Student, Information and Communication Engineering

- · Aizawa-Yamasaki Lab (Multimedia Processing Lab)
- · Photography Club

#### PUBLICATION A Fast Method of Visual Words Assignment of Bag-of-Features for Object 07 / 2015 Recognition

M.-J. Chiou, Y. Toshihiko and K. Aizawa (The University of Tokyo)

Extended Abstract Paper, in The 18th Meeting on Image Recognition and Understanding, Jul. 2015. Source code: https://github.com/coldmanck/A-Fast-Method-of-Visual-Words-Assignment-of-Bag-of-Features-for-Object-Recognition

CERTIFICATIONS	TIONS TOEFL® iBT Test – 84 points Educational Testing Service (ETS)		03 / 2016
	<b>TOEIC</b> ® <b>Test – 810 points</b> Educational Testing Service (ETS)		09 / 2014
	Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) - Level N1 The Japan Foundation		07 / 2013
AWARDS	JASSO Student Exchange Support Program Scholarship Japan Student Services Organization (JASSO)		10 / 2014
	NCTU Short-Term Exchange Scholarship Office of International Affairs, NCTU		10 / 2014
	Xiao Yuan-Long Scholarship Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NCTU		05 / 2014
	Award for Excellence The 8th SUMIKA Cup Japanese Speech Contest, SUMIKA Technolo		04 / 2014 gy co., ltd.
LANGUAGES	Chinese Japanese English	<ul><li>( Native proficiency )</li><li>( Full professional proficiency )</li><li>( Professional working proficiency )</li></ul>	

EXTRACURRICU Vice President
LAR ACTIVITIES Chien-Kuo and T

Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association NCTU

In NCTU, I had been a vice president of "Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association" for a year. I took on leadership roles by organizing a variety of events.

INTERESTS Table tennis, jogging, digital photography, novel and Japanese TV program